

## **Shenin Francies**

Data Science | Medical Engineer

Detail-oriented Data Scientist, with strong analytical and technical skills, guided by the passion to work towards a unified cause. Recent graduate of Medical Engineering that conducts independent researches. Conversant in culture diversity due to exposure to international relations based off of studying and living in India, Kuwait, United Arab Emirates and Germany.

shenin.francies@gmail.com

Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala, India

S sheninfrancis23

#### +91 88 48 44 35 14

in linkedin.com/in/shenin-francies

github.com/SheninFrancies

#### **EDUCATION**

## Biomedical Engineering, MSc Hochschule Furtwangen University

09/2019 - 02/2022

Baden-Württemberg, Germany

Thesis/Project

- Development of electrical measurements for biological tissues
- Temporal Recruitment of lung units and their impact on lung compliance using MATLAB

## **Electrical and Electronics Engineering, BEng** Heriot-Watt University

09/2016 - 11/2019

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

**Projects** 

- Development of a prototype of a user-interactive robot for theme parks in a laboratory environment using C and C++
- Calibration and sequential analysis of differential control of a prototype robot in a laboratory environment using C

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Intern - Data Science and Machine Learning Luminar Technolab

07/2022 - Present Kerala, India

Tasks

- Preprocessed Datasets using Python libraries such as NumPy and Pandas.
- Applied Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning techniques on datasets to derive meaningful insights.
- Familiarized with OpenCV and Deep Learning frameworks such as TensorFlow and Keras.
- Skilled in employing Data visualization tools such as Tableau and PowerBI.

## Research Assistant

### Hochschule Furtwangen University

08/2021 - 09/2021 Baden-Württemberg, Germany

Tasks

- Researched the Two- and Four-Electrode methods in Electrical Impedance Tomography.
- Built circuits, assessed its signal strength and improvised the circuits for optimal performance.

Contact : Dr. Alberto Battistel - baa@hs-furtwangen.de

### **SKILLS**

Python	Data Preprocessing Data Analysis					
Data Visu	Natural Language Processing					
Machine Learning		Tableau		PowerBI	OpenCV	
Keras	TensorFlow		Basics of SQL		MATLAB	
Amazon \	Web Service	es	Projec	Project Management		

#### **PROJECTS**

Application of Machine Learning (09/2022 - 01/2023)

- Implementation of Machine Learning algorithms on various datasets from different domains to analyze the performance metrics of the estimators.
- Key Project: Application of NLP & ML techniques to classify a drug review and evaluate the performance metrics using ROC and Precision-Recall Curve.

## Application of OpenCV and Deep Learning (01/2023 - Present)

Card Validity Extraction using OCR, Application of Filters in Images;
 Training a Neural Network using Keras (In Progress).

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Big Data Foundations - Level 2 (11/2022 - 12/2022)

Certified Practitioner in Project Management (01/2021 - 07/2021)

Excelleter Institute

#### LANGUAGES

Malayalam
Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

French

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Full Professional Proficiency

**Elementary Proficiency** 

## **INTERESTS**

AI in Healthcare

Medical Technology

Literature